Good faith. Good, good faith security
researchers. That's the that's the term.
Best faith security researchers.
I'm going to I'm going to put that in my
I'm going to put that in my Twitter bio
now. Best best faith security
researcher.
Hey everybody, how's it going?
Technogeek here. I just wanted to take a
moment to shout out our episode sponsor
Project Discovery. Project Discovery
makes a lot of different hacking tools.
I'm sure you've at least heard of Nuclei
and that's the one we wanted to focus on
today. They just released version 3.2.
Now, 3.2 has a ton of awesome new
features and the two I wanted to
highlight are authenticated scanning and
the changes to fuzzing support. Now,
authenticated scanning does basically
what you'd expect. You can finally now
authenticate into applications
automatically with Nuclei. You can
leverage either the built-in uh existing
login templates that they've included or
you can make your own and you can use
all of your old existing Nuclei
templates to scan on an authenticated
context within an application now.
For fuzzing support, they have now
expanded the fuzzing from just query
parameters all the way out to headers
and cookies and body parameters and
paths and everything that you can
imagine. So, uh you're going to want to
check out what's in this new release.
Again, it's version 3.2 and if you want
to learn more, go to nux.gg/podcast.
Again, that's nux.gg/podcast.
Thanks.
Dude, why is there a link in this doc of
a mobile device server rack?
What What What is What Why did you put
this in here?
What is this?
Okay, so you asked me yesterday, you're
like, "Hey, do you have any interesting
links? Like, do you use Twitter
bookmarks?" And I was like, "I do use
Twitter bookmarks, but I don't think I
have anything useful in there." I opened
it up and
the last thing I'd bookmarked was this
post that I saw of and I just found it
really interesting.
Um so,
I think the the the original thread was
sort of like going through the evolution
of like how sort of this phone
automation stuff has has uh developed
over the last, you know, decade or
whatever.
And it used to be that you'd have like a
real person sitting in front of like
a sheet of plywood with 15
Samsung cheap Samsung phones on it or
whatever and they would just like tap
all all the buttons on like 30 different
screens Talk about the most boring job.
Like, he just get a message and you're
like, "All right, like this post on like
50 different devices." And then you just
go around and tap tap tap tap tap.
It's crazy. Exactly, exactly. So, but
the the one that I I liked was this I
think it's like the latest generation or
whatever, but like
I've never seen anything like this. They
take
real phones and they disassemble them
and they unscrew the main board from
inside the device and then they hook it
up to some special PCB that they
developed and they have they do this
like 20 times and they mount them inside
of a server case so that there's like 15
of these boards just like sitting on
their edge just like mounted next to
each other all plugged into this one
giant board and then you take like a
single USB cable from this box and you
plug it into your computer and you run
the software and you just have like a
display of like, you know, the 30
screens from every single
phone that's mounted inside the server
box and you just click once and it
clicks everywhere.
Yeah, it's super super interesting, but
I guess this is how they're doing it
nowadays with
all the big like bots botnet type of
things or whatever and
Yeah, yeah. And I was I was saying like
back in my day stuff before I got into
bug bounty and stuff, I used to write
bots and the way that I did this was I
just had like a stack of iPhones that I
bought on eBay that I jailbroke
or just like sitting on the floor. And
that's how I used to press the buttons,
huh? Yeah, that's exactly right.
I bet that was
I bet I bet that was a pretty pretty
relevant hacking experience to building
bots for for, you know,
things, let's just say. Yeah, I like
it's very very similar skill set to bug
bounty, just like different
implementation. It's like how how I like
to see it. So,
I think that there's a lot of
Exactly. It's like that same sort of
mindset. Like, I always say security is
a mindset where like hacking is a
mindset where you just have to reframe
how you think about like the same sort
of problems.
Um and I think that's a great example of
it where
like botting and security are like
almost identical. It's just how you
decide to like use the information that
you have, whether you choose to like
exploit it for malicious purposes or
whether you choose to like exploit
of the community, too. So many really
talented botters were anti-botters
uh have gone into security afterwards.
This is an interesting pipeline.
And vice versa as well. I've seen people
go from security and hacking into the
anti-bot space and be like, "Wow, this
is so hard." You know? So. Yeah, yeah,
exactly, exactly. I every once in a
while I get I get the nerd sniped into
that uh into that area again.
That's probably one of the more
I don't know. I imagine that's one of
the more sort of back and forth uh
industries that you've got because like
security is a little bit back and forth.
Like, sometimes you'll actively be like,
"Oh, this person's literally trying to
hack my my website right now or like my
computer right now." But like that's
that those are kind of kind of rare. But
with with botting stuff, I mean,
it's like, are they going to bot this
drop or not? You know? Like, and the
answer's always going to be pretty much
yes, you know? So, they're always going
to be trying to figure out how to get
around it and it's got to be it's
probably one of the more tangible cat
and mouse games you can find in IT.
For sure. It's a really big cat and
mouse game. Like, that was the the
biggest thing that sort of like pulled
me away from it was just like it was
very grindy in that sense where like
it's you versus the security team and in
my opinion the security team always has
an advantage because
from from the attacker's perspective,
they have to reverse engineer how all
these different checks work. From the
security team's perspective, they can
implement like 10 checks and turn on one
of them and then
you know, let it sit and then the hacker
figures out, "Okay, this is how I bypass
one of them." And then the security team
turns on a second one and then Is the
anti-botting thing under the security
team normally? Do you know? Is that like
its own division or is it like a
Yeah, I mean, usually it's either under
security or like trust and safety type
stuff because they're usually like sort
of hand in hand with like anti-fraud,
anti-botting, that that type of
Interesting.
Well, this is the last time I'm letting
you put a a link in the doc, Joel.
I open this up and it's just like a
server rack full of mobile phones. The
most Joel thing I could possibly think
of.
Yeah.
month.
That's great, man.
All right, dude.
Major life lesson here for any of those
listening and for you and for me.
When Shubs tweets something,
you listen to the tweet. I'm a simple
man.
When Shubs tweets, I listen.
You know? And Shubs tweeted out earlier
this week about
I As he said, let me just let me just
read what he said. "I can't believe so
many people are sleeping on this
research. Here's the link."
And when he says something like that,
you got to not sleep on that cuz that's
serious. And lo and behold, I took the
deep dive, I read it and he is correct.
We were fast asleep on this whole or at
least I was. I was fast asleep on this
.NET remoting research that just came
out from code What is it? Code White?
Code White, yeah. Yeah, so it's
interesting cuz most of the time
when the Assetnote team or Shubs is
tweeting about something, it's some
zero-day that they've either reverse
engineered or found and they have like a
big blog post. This was different. This
was just like a blog post and not only
that, it was like a month old. It was It
wasn't like, "Oh, this came out 3 days
ago." Like, when he says sleeping, like
this had come this had been out for
maybe over a month.
time next time tweet it out. Tweet Tweet
that out
right away. As soon as it comes out,
just be like, "Hey, this is amazing.
Everyone should look at this."
But yeah. Yeah, yeah, it's super super
interesting and it the what's cool is
it's not even the first one in this sort
of like series. Like, the Code White had
done another blog post uh like 2 years
ago in 2022 about this same sort of
technology
um from sort of a different perspective.
Um and it's called .NET remoting. So, I
I know that you actually were were
Yeah, yeah, so tell me a little bit
about that cuz I think we have something
special for the for the listeners, too.
um there's
there's a lot of of cool things cool
takeaways from this one. The I'm going
to give a high-level overview of what
this sort of concept is here. Um and and
then we'll kind of go into the new
research that just came out. So, .NET
remoting is essentially if you guys are
familiar with Java RMI uh remote method
invocation. It's very similar to that,
but essentially it allows you to call
functions and expose objects. Let me be
more clear.
Um
to your code on a different server and
it runs that code on that server um
rather than in your your local code
base. Um
And so, you can register these various
classes to be able to be triggered
remotely and then you have the ability
to call those classes over TCP, IPC or
HTTP.
Um And so there's a couple um resources.
We'll create a section in the the show
notes on um
the best resources I could find on this
that got me up to speed on it enough to
pop an RCE last night.
Um or multiple uh
RCEs last night. But um and essentially,
you know, you have those those three
ways of exploiting it. And but the
problem was previously uh before this
research came out in order to ex with
this over HTTP, which is the one that
has the least uh you know, security
controls on it and the one that is most
likely to be exposed due to HTTP
services often being exposed. Um you
needed to know this like arbitrary
string in the URL that gets generated
when um these objects get created. And
if you know this arbitrary string then
you can uh access the that interface and
get it to run instantiate these objects
and run code.
Um
Yeah. Got it.
So the problem then is how do we get
this URL? And that is what this amazing
research that Shubs highlighted and
Marcus Wolftang, I hope I pronounced
that correctly, um
was writing about uh when he released
this leaking object references to
exploit HTTP.NET remoting um article
uh back on February 27th. Um and
essentially, what this does is it takes
advantage of
some error
um stack trace dump that happens when
you you cause an error in this flow. Um
and that stack trace, if the conditions
are correct, will leak uh this URL that
you need, this super important URL. Um
and so there's a couple ways that he did
that and of course he's building on the
back uh of some research by um the IIS
goat Mr. Saroush himself. Um and some
research that he posted. Man, when when
did Saroush
post this this research? I want to say
this was 2000 2019, I think. Yeah.
Yeah.
2019, yeah, March of 2019.
And essentially, there is a trusted and
you know, when I say this, it just feels
so good to say it, man. There there is a
trusted object that you can overwrite in
the HTTP request by setting a header,
right? So what Saroush found was that
you can set the underscore underscore
request verb header when you're sending
an HTTP request. And that will override
the request verb that is in
that that is the trusted request verb
object
in the HTTP request object. Um inside of
uh the IS stuff being processed. Uh in
the .NET processing of HTTP requests.
And what that does is that creates a
mismatch between Okay, you send a get
request and then you set the header, so
it thinks it's a post request. And then
that causes some error which will in
certain situations dump that URL, that
object reference URL that will leak that
that um that URL, that super special URL
that you need access to uh to actually
do this .NET remoting thing. And then
from there, he provides the the team
over at Code White provides this awesome
GitHub repo. I don't know, did I put it
in the doc?
I
Okay, let me go let me go find it right
now. I'll put it in the doc. Um but they
leak they have this awesome GitHub repo
that just makes it super simple to go
and exploit this. Um and it's it's in
this like little note at the end of the
at yeah, it's literally the last line of
the
of the article. It says, "We also
released this GitHub repo, HTTP remoting
object ref leak with additional
resources such as a vulnerable web app
and some pay example exploit payloads
and a script for automated object ref
leaking and payload delivery."
Dude.
And then this is a Python script in
here. It's literally less than 100
lines. Yeah.
just like
Yeah.
Dude, that's awesome.
that. And I just love I just I I I
messaged Marcus on on Twitter and I
said, "Dude, thank you for being so
thorough with this write-up and then
also delivering, you know, like a a
beautiful exploit to GitHub. And thank
you also for putting it at the very end
of this article so that I most people
will skip it if they get intimidated by
this article and then only I will find
it and then I will use it to pop bugs
cuz that's what happened last night cuz
I hit Naggly up. I was like, "All right,
I understand this research. Scan for
this, scan for that." And he he ran, you
know, a scan across his whole you know,
empire of of subdomains or whatever. And
we got a couple hits and we popped some
RCEs. So
That's so awesome. That's so awesome.
And what's cool is so at the very end
initially, this actually didn't have a
CVE. This was just like some research
that was just published in a blog back
in February.
And
a week ago little under a week ago
um
Microsoft reassessed it and they
published a CVE for it and it was
addressed in the January
uh
Let's see, the CVE was addressed by
updates in January 2024, but the CVE was
omitted from the security updates. So I
am wondering if that maybe is how Shubs
picked up on this. Um cuz this was on
March 22nd when the CVE was released by
Microsoft and maybe maybe the team over
there is just keeping a close eye on the
Microsoft
is also
Yeah, I feel like Shubs is also like a
shark with this stuff. So like anytime
anything IIS or .NET related, you know,
comes up, he's like
you know, it's like a it's like a
piranha in the water, you know, um to
those sort of things.
Sorry to represent you that way, Shubs,
but it's like I mean he just he knows
all of the things about IIS related
stuff and .NET related stuff. So any of
that Windows um
HTTP stack uh
things. So I wouldn't be surprised if he
was on top of this as soon as it came
out.
Yeah, I I do love um
how how much like sort of it's not
necessarily new research, right? Like it
is, but it isn't. Like the core research
itself is, but a lot of the stuff that
it's based on, like the blog from
Saroush, for example, that blog is now 5
years old uh from the NCC Group One from
Saroush and talking about this same sort
of technology that even their previous
blog post from Code White was uh 2 years
old. So
it's really interesting. I mean, we
talked about this over and over again
that just because something is a couple
years old research-wise doesn't mean
that it's out of date or um irrelevant
or non-applicable and taking the time to
read through those research, even if
it's, you know, 5 years old, you see
something 5 years old and you're like,
"Oh, well, this probably won't apply
today." It probably does actually and
you should read through it.
And and I always love when people
continue to build on their past research
because you know, the the Code White
team at this point after having done
this in in uh what did you say, 2 years
ago? So 2022. Um you know, they have a a
knowledge set on this on this topic that
is you know, very exclusive to them and
maybe a couple other people in the
world, you know. And so they they are
carrying the burden of like All right,
if there's going to be innovation in
this area, it should probably be me. You
know, and they continue to build upon
that research and build upon that
research until they find a way like this
to leak
these these object references and and
get access to that that secret URL. Very
cool. I really like it.
Yeah, super super cool.
Um Awesome. Should we go to the the next
the next link?
hit me with it, man.
Okay. So this is this is a fun one. Um
This doesn't happen almost ever. Uh
there was a DOM Purify bug.
So it was it this is always juicy cuz I
woke up uh a couple days ago and
somebody in our one of our mutual group
chat had posted it's like, "Babe, wake
up. The new DOM Purify bypass
just dropped." And I was like, "Whoa,
that's crazy." And there's a really
really cool blog from um
Oh, what's her name? I literally just
had it open.
Uh Slonser?
Yeah, that's it. I opened Yeah, Slonser.
Both on Twitter and and their blog
Slonser_ um and their blog is
blog.slonser.info.
So essentially, this is
a bit of a niche bypass. Um the main
thing here is that it has to do with
passing in uh element object into the
DOM Purify um sanitize function. So you
can both pass in a string that is just
like HTML and it will sanitize that, or
you can pass in an actual object
reference. Like if you do like
document.createElement,
you can pass that actual variable into
DOM Purify sanitize and it'll do the
same thing.
And one of the interesting things that
he noticed is that when it basically
back parses or forward parses, whatever,
converts it into a string or from a
string into the actual element nodes, it
checks the types of the elements and
does certain processing on every single
one. And
there it has the capability to sanitize
and parse XML as well as HTML. And there
are some core key differences between
XML and HTML when it's getting parsed
and when it's getting rendered by the
browser and
individually. And so what this
researcher found is that
if you pass in these special XML tags,
you know how XML has like the the open
arrow question mark and it does like
open arrow question mark sets the you
know, what version it is
There's a couple weird tags in XML,
right? There's like the
What is it? The ones we use for for XXE
all the time, the CData ones. And then
there's also these are like uh
These are processing instruction tags,
right?
Right, yeah. So they're they're referred
to specifically as processing
instructions. And you can basically
think of think of them as sort of like
metadata, that really just tells the
processor how it's you know, processor
instructions, right? It tells it how how
it should be processed rather than
you know, directly just sort of
inferring a lot of that stuff.
Um and so DOMPurify has to handle this.
And the way that it does handle this is
by essentially replacing those tags with
HTML comment tags. All right, and so you
have a little bit of a confusion here
where it's going from XML to HTML in the
rendering in the sanitization process
where it's sort of passively just say,
"Oh, this should be treated as HTML."
But as we mentioned, there are core
differences between how XML and HTML are
both interpreted and rendered by the
browser. So when you put this stuff
inside of like an SVG tag for example,
you can do all sorts of really fun
things.
And the TLDR is that if you open with
these processing uh instructions, and
then you just leave an empty
closing arrow or closing, you know,
bracket in there or whatever, it the it
doesn't properly sanitize it and so it
allows you to escape that into an HTML
context and you can insert, you know,
image elements that trigger on error and
all that kind of stuff there just
directly within the SVG. Um actually
it's not within the SVG, outside of the
SVG. It lets you break out of the SVG.
Huh.
Yeah, super super interesting. Um and I
think part of the root cause, uh at
least in the beginning, was the fact
that when it filters through the element
nodes that it's that that you feed into
the sanitize function, it
has selectors for specific types like
should it allow comments, should it
allow elements, should it allow
processing instructions. And processing
instructions was not um enabled by
default. And so what, you know, it
caused it to sort of have this behavior
where it wasn't handling it correctly,
it was handling it in a very specific
way uh as if it was like HTML.
And so that was the initial fix. And
then I think that there there was
actually a bypass um
to just based on sort of like how
DOMPurify is configurable, you can um
have these different checks
uh that look for different tag names and
stuff. And you can again, you can bypass
it um using a similar sort of you know,
you use a custom tag name and you do the
same sort of attack where you close it
early
um and you can get it to, you know, pull
pull this custom data out of the
elements and uh and again trigger an Ah,
you're using a custom tag name instead
of the the processing instructions for
Okay, got you. Yeah, yeah. Uses this
Yeah, it has this like special custom
element handling configuration thing.
And one thing I will notice, I think
I I think they actually mentioned this
as well. This isn't super common, like
the configuration and the and the use
case here, but it is still a bypass and
it's still really really interesting
data.
And I think you actually mentioned that
we won't name them, but somebody that
you know and I know
uh managed to actually find some
bypasses.
I did get permission, so Udyota uh
Udyotak
a I guess is his handle uh but Udyota's
his name. He uh he saw this and he's,
you know, just the brain just starts
spinning and spinning and spinning. And
so he he actually found some some
bypasses to this as well.
So this is uh you know, one a bypass,
then a a another bypass and a fix, and
then Udyota also has some some bypasses.
So this um this processing instructions
thing seems to have been the
the core of a lot of really tricky
functionality as far as HTML parsing
goes and HTML sanitization goes. So I
bet in other libraries there's also
similar problems if they're also
including uh
HT or XML with the HTML when they're
trying to do the sanitization. So
definitely definitely some cool
takeaways there. And the processing
instructions thing I I wasn't familiar
with this, I didn't think until I
realized that Sorry.
The uh processing instruction uh that
you see at the beginning of every single
XML block, you know, like if you're
going to do an XXE it's just like, you
know, Yeah. Yeah, angle bracket question
mark XML. Yeah, and it like defines that
this is like an XML document and you can
define like the the um
like UTF-8 or whatever.
Yeah, encoding and stuff.
And so you see it almost all the time. I
just hadn't really been like, "Oh, what
is that?" yet. So I'm glad for people
like Slonser that that are
think, "Oh, what is that?" and go
research it and find cool stuff like
this cuz uh this is definitely a really
sweet bypass.
Yeah, exactly. And and maybe something
for the listener.
It I do wonder how this works for other
thing like PHP I think is a great
example which also does a similar thing
where it has those sort of like
processing not really processing
instructions, but like that prefix type
of stuff. And perhaps other
similar instances of this behavior may
also be vulnerable to bad
implementations or um you know, like
weird tricky situations like this where
you can feed double tags and get it to
parse correctly.
I'm looking forward to seeing um
Udyota's write-up. He's going to release
it within the next couple weeks, so I'm
excited for that bad boy.
Awesome. Awesome. Yeah, I love uh it
it's awesome. I mean, the Cure53 team
the in the blog it says that they fixed
it like same day. Uh
I mean, like almost immediately.
Um so super cool. I know I think we know
at least one person over on that team um
who's doing really cool stuff, so shout
out to the Cure53 team. Shout out to
DOMPurify, super awesome. Uh you know,
even even when they make a little
mistake, they uh they address it very
elegantly and
as I I love the DOMPurify team, man, it
hurts me on a on a on a weekly basis to
see their their tool properly
implemented in so many places. It's
like, "No, it's DOMPurify. Give up."
You know.
It is everybody every bug hunter's dream
to get like a DOM a DOMPurify bypass.
That's on the like uh what what are the
bug hunter bingo chart or whatever of
like, all right, let me DOMPurify
bypass, RCE, you know,
zero day that I can spray across hack my
wife bypass. Well, and also so speaking
of WAFs, we'll just jump down a little
bit to the to the second to last item on
the on the list here.
Um
so I was poking around on a target the
other day and I'm
I don't know why. I've seen this
endpoint like 50 bajillion times, but
the whole um
Cloudflare/cdn-cgi
thing kind of stood out to me cuz it's
like, "Okay,
essentially what's happening here
is um you know, you've got Cloudflare in
front, it's a WAF.
And then you know, that WAF needs to
have some client-side resources so that
it can do things like uh you know,
enforce a CAPTCHA or something like
that.
Excuse me.
And uh and so what it does is it injects
this endpoint /cdn-cgi
on all of the, you know, websites it
protects and then it hosts its own
custom stuff there like JS files and and
that sort of thing. Um logging endpoints
and that sort of thing. Um so I was
looking at this and I'm like, "Wow, this
is uh super weird." And I feel like if
we can hack this, then we can hack like
every website, you know? Uh because
every website that has Cloudflare has
this on in front of it. And so I started
researching it and there's like um a
documentation endpoint uh documentation
endpoint, man. Such such hacker
terminology there, dude. Uh a
documentation page
on um
on, you know, what this endpoint is. And
essentially it lists five um uses for
this endpoint. It says, "Okay, you can
hit /cdn-cgi/trace."
Which one is super cool cuz it like
kicks back information about your
request and it it's in like text plain
content type, but um
that could be helpful for something for
sure. Um so there's that. Uh there's
JavaScript detection, uh that's the
that's the bot product thing
uh that that prevents botting. Um
there's image transformations, which I
was like, "Okay, okay, now we're talking
here." So I I I
So like there's ways that you can like
do
like um
uh transforming of images and converting
of images. And I went in here and it's
like supported input formats, SVG.
Supported output formats, SVG.
And I was like, "Hmm,
that's interesting." So I I went in
there and I was like poking around at it
for a long time.
And I was like, "Man, I wonder if
there's any you know, any bugs here, any
ways to bypass." And I was actually
thinking like, "Okay, SVG XML like we
just talked about the DOMPurify bypass.
Let me see if I can like try some cool
stuff with that." So I was like writing
that out, wasn't working. And of course,
who do I turn to? The master of
Cloudflare, Mr. Udyota himself that we
just talked about.
And and Udyota's like, "Oh yeah, I I
assessed that like, you know, months
ago.
Uh there's a super duper tight uh
freaking CSP on it."
I was like, "Shoot." So I went there and
I looked and lo and behold, it's like
default-src 'none'.
Which is like like what are you going to
be able to do with that? Um
and and so the SVG endpoint might be a
little bit of a dead end, but there's
also a bunch of other things here and
there've been bugs found here before by
the the PortSwigger team um back in 2017
and then also by our boy uh Masato
Kinugawa
um found a like global CSP bypass on any
website that uses uh Cloudflare back in
uh 2017. And I just haven't I I
researched around and I haven't seen a
bunch of research on this specific
endpoint since like, you know, 2017-ish
time. So I feel like it's time to look
at this again because I feel like there
could be some CSP bypasses here um
and at least uh if not CSP bypasses, at
least some cool gadgets that could be
used to hack some stuff in some pretty
neat circumstances. We just got to
enumerate every single file that is or
every single endpoint that's under that
/cdn cgi place.
Yeah, for sure. Um it's cool to see this
tweet all the way back from August 2017.
This is I think even before I started
bug bounty cuz I started in August of
2017 at like a live hacking event. So
uh this this is probably like a couple
weeks before I even started doing bug
bounty, but it's really cool to see
um just the sort of you know
about the one from Mastodon? just like
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, this tweet just
being like, "Hey, by the way, here's
like a Cloudflare CSP bypass that I
found like the weird behavior." Um and
it it reminds me a lot of this other
link
um from Malwok uh on Twitter that was
talking about these XSS that that um
that he found
where this CDN uh of of the of the
target of the of the program
um is like cdn.example.com or whatever.
And that's explicitly out of scope, but
while they were looking at in-scope
targets, they noticed that there was a
lot of endpoints that would use a slash
version of it where they would go, you
know, example.com/cdn
Mhm. um slash
file.js or whatever. And because of that
uh by popping something on the CDN by
finding an available file that they
could upload and and essentially
control, they were able to use that same
path scheme to pull their
attacker-controlled file from the CDN
directly and get an XSS on all these uh
different domains.
And that just reminds me so much of this
CDN CGI endpoint because it's very very
similar. I wonder if it might even have
been
sketchy, man. And and like it it it
makes you think like, "Okay." Especially
in this I I have seen this scenario a
bunch of times where it's like, "Okay,
they're reverse proxying to their CDN."
And like they're saying it's out of
scope, but actually we can just upload
any file that we've uploaded to the CDN
we can just access on any given host.
I've seen that plenty of times before.
Um so that's a great general principle.
But also this concept of like reverse
proxying to CDNs, you know, in the
Cloudflare scenario, in in this scenario
that Malwok is talking about it's
sketchy, man. It's it's sketchy because
you know, CDNs they're supposed to
host content, you know? And and if that
content can be affected by other users,
you're just letting people upload
arbitrary content to be hosted
potentially on any other website that
uses that same CDN if there's a reverse
proxy.
Yeah, for sure. And I think it's really
interesting. Um I mean like just that
behavior in general, like the path
routing to like subdomains and stuff is
super weird. Like that screams reverse
proxy problems, secondary context
problems, all sorts of weird things. So
um you know, that's one of those things
to keep an eye out for like definitely
probably more than XSS. You could you
could find a lot more It's a great
point. Another thing that I've kind of
seen with this format is like what will
happen is sometimes these CDNs need to
be are like signed URL protected or
whatever, right? And you need to get uh
a signed URL for anything. And but when
you're accessing it via like a a certain
path on a on a website, it's just using
like whatever god token or whatever that
gives it access to that that S3 bucket
or whatever that backend is. And um one,
if you can cause some sort of error and
get it to leak that uh token, then
that's big bucks. Um but two, if you can
just do a path traversal, if you can get
the the reverse proxy to normalize um
and and hit a path traversal. It's a
little bit tricky with S3 because S3
doesn't do do traversals.
Um but if you can figure out a way to
get that to to work and you can hit any
endpoint without having to, you know,
have a signed URL or office associated
with it, then a lot of times there's a
lot of sensitive information you can
leak as well.
Yeah, for sure. I I love that to token
leaking thing cuz we've seen that many
times at live hacking events where it's
not even like a crazy complex bug. It's
it's it's almost like a stack trace.
It's like you know, like the the least
suspecting thing that you would you
would think to become like a super
critical bug.
But all it takes is that, you know, it's
that one token or that one
overprivileged method of access and an
accidental error trace and and it's GG.
forget this one time like there was an
endpoint that a couple people found that
was allowing you to do some traversing
and that sort of thing. Um and uh on on
a backend host and you could access
files you weren't supposed to be able to
access. And it it was like it was like
very impactful. It it was definitely,
you know, a higher crit already. And
then Nagli comes along
and he just I don't know, being the big
brain boy he is, he like sticks a a
collaborator, you know, domain in there
in like a spot that doesn't make any
sense to put it in, right? And somehow
he gets a hit on that domain instead of
on the actual like backend host. And
then that that that that, you know, hit
the SSRF hit
you couldn't do like um like full read
or anything. But that SSRF hit had the
auth token for that that back server
attached to it. He used that auth token
to log into that back that backend
server and you can just dump everything,
which is so much more impactful because
you didn't need to know the URL, you
know, the path of the thing that we were
trying to leak on the backend.
That's so interesting. Another place
where I see this type of pattern a lot
is mobile apps, actually. Where a lot of
times for mobile app authentication,
right? Typically it's not cookies, it's
like an auth token or something like
that.
Like a header. And um
they forget to add an auth check. And so
they just add it like they have it added
at sort of a middleware level across the
entire request HTTP client that they're
using. And it'll just add it to every
single cuz they assume, "Oh, this is
just going to all our trusted hosts."
But if you can find a way to control the
host or, you know, make it redirect or
something like that. Well, we've talked
about redirects a little bit, but
Depending on how it's how it's
implemented.
Um
pain.
Yeah, that one still exists a little
bit.
Oh, good.
But um but a lot of the times it'll get
added automatically and all you have to
do is be able to control the host and
you get a full account takeover because
that auth co-
that auth token or that auth cookie or
whatever is getting set on every single
request. And all you have to do is be
able to control where that request is
going and it's GG.
big. It's almost like client-side path
traversal.
Um
for the client-side on the mobile apps,
right?
Yeah. Yep. Yeah. Yeah, exactly. Which
we've also seen.
we have. So it it that just I don't
know, man. I hate to cuz it it's helpful
to categorize all these different
things, you know, like client-side path
traversal and like, you know, SSRF and
blah blah blah. But at the end of the
day it's like
look, if you can make something hit your
server
uh
you know, be aware of the context in
which that can happen, you know, like
that can happen in the browser, happen,
you know, in the victim's browser, it
can happen in the uh you know, the
mobile app or the the server. And then
just read everything, you know, about
that request that you can possibly read.
Um
and look at all the hints, look at all
the little tokens, look at all the
cookies that are getting passed along
because um there's a decent chance that
something could be really sensitive
there.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, absolutely.
Absolutely.
Let's see. What do we got?
I want you I want you to talk about XSS
Doctor cuz there was some really awesome
uh collaboration that happened in the
Critical Thinkers channel on the Discord
and uh
and it led to a blog post and a couple
other things. So so why don't you talk
Doctor was um
such a valued member of the Critical
Thinking community was chatting in the
in the Critical Thinkers chat on the
Discord. And he was talking about he's
like, "Oh, guys, I found this like
really cool way to like reverse uh
JavaScript uh de-obfus- or
JavaScript obfuscation." Um and I was
like, "Dude, you got to write this up.
Like this is helpful for somebody." This
is exactly what we talk about on the pod
all the time, which is like, "Look, even
if it isn't a crazy vuln, if you spend
some time and you figured something out
then um and you're so inclined, you
know, I'm not going to tell everybody to
write up everything, but like and you're
so inclined
write that up. It has a lot of value to
share things like that because um you
know, people can build on the back of
that. Just like we saw with the .NET
remoting thing, how, you know, the the
Code White team built on the you know,
on the back of Saroush and then they
built on their own stuff. And it just it
keeps on building and building and the
more we can sort of help foster that
environment, it's really good. So I
said, um "Listen, JD, you got to you got
to write this up." So he wrote it up
and he's he's got a uh got to post it on
Medium. We'll we'll link it down in the
description. But essentially, what he uh
did was he released a script and sort of
explained what was going on with a very
common uh JS obfuscation scheme. And
essentially, what it is is they
those jerks
take all all the [__]
everything helpful from a JavaScript
file and they just stick it in one
massive array, right? And then they they
say to themselves, "Okay, how can I make
this [__] as complicated as possible?"
And so they make this like decryption
function that that's like, "Okay, we're
going to take in a hex value, not a not
a not a decimal value, a hex value, just
just to be a little shit." And uh and
then we're going to we're going to do a
certain amount of like shifts and
pushes, you know, to like rotate the
order of this array
Yep. uh this many times. And then we're
going to do some math and then we're
going to like you know, spit out uh a
value from this array and that's the the
thing you're looking for, you know, in
this sort of obfuscation scheme. And um
and so essentially, JD very
painstakingly stepped through all of
that, explained how all this works and
how common of a of a JS obfuscation
scheme this is uh a sort of format this
is, and he includes a script on how to
um
how to un-obfuscate
scripts that use this this method. And
he showed me the results of uh you know
the before and after of the script, and
man does it increase readability um in
these sort of super obfuscated
situations. Uh so I think this is really
helpful for anybody who's dealing with
highly obfuscated JS.
Yeah, and I love I love the sort of the
basic simple knowledge sharing aspect
that you talked about. I mean like we do
that. I mean that's half of what this
podcast is, just like us talking about
like random little things and tips and
tricks and stuff that we've come across
and learned throughout the years of
doing bug bounty, and
having, you know, other people just sort
of write those things down and share it
is so valuable because the same people
who are listening to this podcast also
want to consume that data, right? They
want those little tips and tricks that
they can put in their in their notebook
or put in the back of their head, and
then when they encounter something like
that, they can say, "Oh, I have a thing
for that. Let me Let me go, you know, I
I don't need to waste my time figuring
out how this works. Let me just
read that XSS doctor blog post really
quick and and and do the same thing and
make this easier and and cut to the
chase."
Um
the other thing is I see this all the
time, again, in mobile apps. Mobile apps
do this all the time, a string
obfuscation.
And I imagine you could probably do a
similar thing in JavaScript. What I like
to do in
in Android is I just use Frida and I
hook and I call the function directly
and I just pass in the obfuscated string
that I have in the source code, and
I'll just, you know, take the the
decoded or decrypted output or whatever,
and I'll just replace it in the source
so that I can know what it is. The other
thing I'll sometimes do is I'll hook it,
and I'll either replace the function
with like a wrapper or something like
that, and I'll just log all the inputs
and outputs and say, "Oh, this this
obfuscated input equals this
de-obfuscated output."
And then either I can do a match and
replace throughout my entire source, and
I can replace all the instances of it,
or if I'm, you know, I come across
something encrypted, instead of having
to run that function manually, I can
just control F for it in the output of,
you know, my console or whatever, and I
can see
Yeah, the the wrapper's a good idea. And
then he he mentioned something in there,
too. It's like, "Okay, so this function
is called, you know, A3C or whatever,
right?" And and and sometimes they call
it A3C directly, but sometimes they'll
do like let CD equal A3C, and then
they'll call CD or something like that.
And it's like, "Come on, could you just
like Could you not? Could you please not
do that?"
Yeah, exactly. So that's the one thing
about the wrapper, right? The wrapper,
if you wrap that that underlying
function, then regardless of how it gets
called, then it's still going to log it.
Um so that that's pretty nice, but yeah,
obfuscation is always just It's one of
those security through obscurity things
that I never really agree with because
it
like
what is it doing? It's making it more
difficult to understand what's going on
from an outside perspective, but there's
no actual like security
implications there, right? Like you're
not making it from a back inside. Like
if you're trying to prevent somebody
from abusing your APIs, then prevent
them from abusing your APIs from the API
side, right? Add server-side checks, add
additional verification methods, all
sorts of stuff that make it more
difficult to abuse the APIs. Don't just
make it more difficult to read. Um but
maybe that's my naive
No, no, no, I mean like look look Dude,
I I
I want to agree with you. And don't get
me wrong, in a report many times I I
have I have dissed security by obscurity
and be like, "You can't rely on security
by obscurity." You know, like very
passionately arguing for security or
against
security by obscurity. But recently I'm
realizing like, listen, so much of this
industry
you know, at its core is just about not
being the easiest target to to pop,
right? You know, like like
And I think most of the people that are
running bug bounty programs are already
kind of being on that point, I'd
imagine, you know, where it's like
they're not the easiest, you know, one
to get into or whatever, but
um
Just
riddle me this, Joel. You know
Riddle me this, Joel. If if you're
hacking a target
and you put wrong one wrong
parameter, and it returns a 404, how
does that make you feel?
That makes you feel terrible, doesn't
it?
When when when there's no error page,
it's just it's just a 404. You know,
there's no 500 error, there's no 400,
there's no like 403. Am I not
authorized? Who knows? It's just a 404,
you know? How about wild How about wild
card subdomains? And so it's like it's
like, you know, anything you can do like
that, you know, JS obfuscation, 404 uh
you know, error pages and stuff like
that, rather than actual 500s or
whatever, or or 403s even, right? Like
you're when when you do a 403, you're
letting the attacker know, "Hey, you're
not authorized to do this."
you know? And that that gives them
information, where you could just say
Yeah. Don't know, you know?
And so Do you think that there's a
remedy for this from like to to make it
easier for security researchers though?
Cuz like on one hand, like from an from
for attackers, like yeah, it's dangerous
to not have those things in place when
like someone's coming from a malicious
intent perspective, but then if you have
sort of that best intent perspective and
you want to make it easier for
researchers,
like what do you Is there
Do you have any tips or any ideas?
best intent, not not good intent, you
know? The normally the the phrase is
like good intent security research, but
we we have the best intent.
But
yeah, so I I think pretty much the only
solution to that from this perspective
is like having a private VIP program, if
you're a public program. Because if
you're a public program, you can't
release to everyone like, "Hey, just add
this header and it'll like turn all the
404s into 500s or whatever, right?"
Yeah. Cuz
cuz then, you know, the hacker's just
going to be like "Thank you very much."
You know?
I am a security researcher. That's
right. I have lost my way.
Um but
yeah, if you run a private VIP program
with the people that are going to be
adding the most value to your to your
program with vetted,
you know, people on it, you know,
HackerOne background checked or
whatever, and have a track record of
being, you know,
best intent security researchers,
um
then
Not just good, but the best.
Um
yeah, no, good faith. Good good faith
security research. That's the That's the
term. Best faith security researchers.
I'm going to I'm going to put that in my
I'm going to put that in my Twitter bio
now. Best Best faith security
researcher.
Um
I'm not even good, I'm just the best.
Yeah, so
anyway,
uh then then you can release, you know,
some sort of header or something that's
going to undo all that, and you can
release, you know, unobfuscated JS files
and stuff like that. So I don't know,
man. It's a little bit of a It's a
little bit of a trade-off. Obviously,
all of that takes time and effort away
from actually securing the product as
well, right? Because at the end of the
day
uh it's not that hard to sort of intuit
how some of this this functionality is
going to be working, you know, if
there's like an ID parameter, and ID
parameter, you know, equals
you know, somebody's ID, and then you
put in somebody else's ID. If it's not a
403, it's a 200, then you have to return
a 200. You know, at the end of the day,
you're still going to run into issues
like that, so um
whether it's worth it or not, I'm not
sure, but um
it definitely pisses me off.
So I imagine it'd piss off other
hackers.
Me too.
Yeah, absolutely. Okay, we have two We
have two more tweets, and I wanted to
save
um Naffy's for the end um to discuss
that. So let's go over Rennie Pax's
um cool little technique here. I think
this is This is just one of those little
gadgets for like proving impact, I
think. That's That's just a a nice
little one.
I I wanted to ask you about this, Joel,
because um so Rennie Pax tweeted, "To
make your XSS less conspicuous, you can
hide your payload by updating URL path
with a valid URL." And I think this is
just something a lot of people don't
know you can do. So if you run
history.pushState
and then as a third parameter provide a
path, it will stay on the same page that
you're on.
Um you know, like you you will remain in
control of the DOM,
but the path will be updated.
The path in URL bar will be updated to
whatever you provide it.
And that's just pretty weird. Yeah, for
sure. And you see this You see this
actually on a lot of websites without
probably even realizing it. Um
basically, anything that's changing your
your URL without a full page load or a
redirect is doing this.
Um I think YouTube does this a lot.
page applications work.
Yeah, all the single page applications
are using, you know, push um local
storage push state or whatever the
function is.
Yeah, it And so And so I don't know. I
wanted to talk to you about this, like
um one, I think a great tweet, really
helpful, brings brings light to
something that a lot of people might not
be aware of being possible.
Uh but also like I feel like there's a
whole set of like
attacker-like practices like this that
you can implement into your POCs that
just bring more impact. And what I've
realized lately is like when you model a
full attack path and you make it
extremely clear, um that hits harder
with the team. I I have a bug that
recently got paid 150% of what it
normally would get paid cuz we we found
a bug similar to this many times, and
you know, we submit it, they always pay
the same amount for it every time, but
this time I was like, "All right, let me
take this a little bit further. I'm
going to explain how I would distribute
this payload given, you know, the
functionality on the website. I'm going
to explain how um I would exploit this
once the user, you know,
uh clicks on the link or whatever, um
and how, you know, how I would worm it
essentially.
Um so I I described that and it got paid
150% what it normally gets paid.
Um
And so I think there's this whole
concept of like
making your attacks
have
more visual impact that I think is a
little bit underestimated and I might
might have been and I do pretty good
POCs and like I
that's what I something that I consider
to be my one of my my strong points, but
I think you can even take it even
further and just describe the whole
attack path um and how you would exploit
this at a a scale and I think that will
really increase impact. Yeah.
Yeah, for sure. I mean, I think um
it really depends on the program, right?
So some programs are really good about
saying like we know what impact is like
we can we can tell that from this point
here's what the ultimate impact would be
of your vulnerability. We're going to
pay it out as such. However, I would say
that's not
Mhm. the norm. Most programs probably
aren't going to do that. Most programs
are going to say, here's the impact you
demonstrated we're going to pay you as
such.
Um you know, if you have an XSS, but you
don't show that you can steal cookies
and do an ATO, they're going to pay it
as an XSS, not an ATO, right? Um uh
because I mean, for a lot of reasons,
right? Like it's not in their it's not
really in their
best interest to escalate a
vulnerability for you like even further.
Like they probably know that that that
that issue is there. Um
but you know, from
from the research research research
researcher's perspective, you want to
sort of demonstrate um the highest
impact you can. So that is
also sort of that benefit of hacking on
one program is that you develop those
gadgets and those impact scenarios
yourself where you can say, oh, anytime
I have an XSS, I can create an ATO. Like
they have this systemic problem or um
whatever it is.
And you can demonstrate that that
impact. Um
in other cases, it might not, you know,
be worth it, right? Like for the time
and effort or whatever it takes to to
escalate that vulnerability further like
versus just like having, you know, if
you know the program and you know that
they're going to handle it well,
spending an extra 4 hours or something
to try and escalate your your XSS to
some, you know, further bug may not be
worth the effort. It's the juice worth
the squeeze is is the phrase that I
always like. Um and so I think it you
know, it kind of depends program by
program, but you should always try and,
you know, if you have the ability to put
a higher impact scenario. I mean,
imagine, right? Like if you have an XSS
and you have an ATO, why would you only
report the XSS, right? You're you're
always going to report the higher impact
scenario. So if you have those easy
opportunities, yeah, yeah, if you have
those easy easy opportunities,
like chase them down, you know,
hedge your time and stuff so that you're
you're not spending too much time on on
something that's not worth it, but, you
know, escalate your bugs as best as you
can and then when you feel like you're
there, go ahead and submit it and uh
that's that's always my recommendation.
but not this is something Nagli does
well, which which just eeks eeks me a
little bit.
Oh, yeah. Um 100%.
freaking eeks me a little bit, man, cuz
like whenever we collab, he's like,
Justin, why why aren't you writing a
good report? What you need to write a
better report for them to like Yeah, his
title his title is like pre-auth full
RCE access to source code and uh
and it's like an XSS.
You know, like and he does he does take
it a little over the top sometimes, but
he tells a good story, you know, and he
and he and he outlines the attack path,
so
I think what what Ramin Pad did here was
like he provided another way for you to
make it seem more like an actual attack
and you know, if you look in your in
your URL bar and there's like, you know,
script blahdy blahdy blah, you know,
then it might not be the most um
uh you know, convincing attack, uh but
if you if you update that using
history.pushState, then you can make
something look very benign and uh you
know, people could not even realize
they're on a certain page.
Uh so It's it's
it's it's it's definitely a a good
technique and there's other things as
well like um
like closing your your sort of um
conspicuous windows after you do CSRFs
with them and not just leaving it open
on the like, you know, company's
successfully updated object page or
whatever.
Yeah. Um that sort of thing.
Um
and I I think just
like I said before, it just feels good
to give a fully polished POC and I think
um
Yeah. those of you that haven't fully
fully fleshed out like a banger of a POC
before, you should give it a shot
because it feels amazing to submit that
report and see your work sort of
manifest before you.
Yeah, and also from the program side,
it's it's really nice when you can just
like click one link and see the full
impact there, right? Like when a
researcher says step one, click this
link, step two, ATO, like that's
awesome, right? And so like both the
satisfaction for you as well as the
program of like there's no question in
anybody's mind what the impact is here,
what the bug is here, like it is very
very clear that this is a vulnerability
and that it's exploitable and that it
has impact and that's just going to make
your triage process faster, it's going
to make the payout process faster, it's
going to make your experience
communicating with the program team
faster and easier and better. Like
everything's just better. So if you have
a banger POC,
do it. Do it. Like do it, make it as
good as you can and always put out the
best POC you can cuz
and like the the the flip side, the
converse is you you create a POC that's
like lackluster and there's like 10, 15
steps. You're going to be going back and
forth with triage trying to get them to
produce it. You're going to be going
back and forth with the program trying
to get them to understand the impact and
how it works. Like
it
make everybody's life easier, your own
included and put a put a great POC
together. That's my recommendation.
Um so where do we want to go with with
the with the Naffy's Naffy's tweet? You
want to you want to launch that one off
or should I launch that one off?
Sure. Sure. Sure. Well, I'll read it and
then I know you had a question about it.
So
um Naffy made a tweet um this was a week
ago
um and he said, I I think the idea of
keeping it simple is especially true for
web testing. Long before you start
trying to implement complex techniques,
you need to get that get down the basics
of one, what are the assets? Recon,
subdomains, IP ranges. Two, what can I
see on those assets? Root forcing, are
they APIs? How are they reached? Is it
root forceable, etc.
When Naffy first started hacking, um
Yahoo's all that he used to do. He would
run Nmap and Dirsearch for days and find
random ass directories that were old
legacy apps and hack on those apps. And
he says that there's nothing wrong with
complexity, but I have largely remained
immune to the movements of application
security. This is the most significant
thing I think I've added to my
methodology for the last years is
checking for secondary context
reversals. If you're doing just those
two things well with any kind of volume
or repetition repetition, you should be
finding things. I know that I still do
and I'm largely doing the same things.
Yeah, dude.
So so like
Go ahead.
This is not where I thought he was going
with this tweet, right? If you read you
read it in the beginning, he says, and
this is where the tweet cuts off, right?
He says, long before you start trying to
implement complex techniques, you need
to get down the basics of and then the
tweet cuts, right? And it goes to like
the the next tweet. I was like, okay.
All right, Naffy. Like like you tell
them and then I clicked in that tweet
and he's like, recon. And I'm like, okay
okay, you know, but okay, I see that.
And I know that Naffy's a really like
recon heavy dude and he does and man is
he like one of the most talented recon
guys out there. Like he really just Yep.
I saw him I worked with him a little bit
on a live hacking event once on an older
company specifically on an older company
and he's just like really really coming
up with good stuff.
Um
Yep. And I think recon is important
understanding um
you know, what assets there are to
attack, but to I think
before you do all that, you know, you
need to get down the basics of hacking.
You know, you you need to get down the
basics of like, okay, once I find these
assets,
what am I going to do with them? And and
like uh
how do I how do I find an XSS? How do I
find an access control thing? And like
and like
yeah, I think I think there's there's
very clearly multiple
types of hackers even more so than I
used to used to think so and the results
are really excellent for both, you know,
like you get the the J Haddix and the
Naffy type um
where they're they're really just like
going heavy on the recon, going heavy on
the scanning, going heavy on the on the
um
you know, brute forcing the the sub or
the um directories and that sort of
thing, finding all the APIs. I like how
Naffy called out APIs here. Are there
APIs? How are they reached? How are they
accessible? That's a good call out. Um
Yep. But there's those kind of people
and then there's the people that are,
you know, working on the business logic
of the applications and I just feel like
working on the business logic of the
applications is a better place to start.
What What do you What do you think about
that?
Yeah, for sure. I So I what I liked
about this like I read this and I pulled
sort of different different conclusions
that Naffy did from from his own tweet,
right? So Naffy was like, oh, you should
like do recon, like you figure out the
assets, like are they root forceable and
stuff? Like yeah, like kind of, but
that's like
that's the recon approach, right? And I
think if you're Naffy and you hunt like
Naffy, that is the right place to
approach it. That is the right that is
the right way and I also think Naffy's
oversimplifying his own process by
saying, you know, like, oh, is this root
forceable? Are there patterns? Like that
takes decades of context and experience
that Naffy has that makes it really
really easy for him to do that and he
does that really well because of that.
So when he looks at an API and he goes,
oh, there's like a weird pattern here.
Like that clicks for him immediately.
That's not going to click for everybody
immediately when you see sort of these
routing things. That just is from years
and years and years of him
looking at different APIs, especially
legacy ones, right? The stuff that he's
really good at hacking on and
identifying those common patterns um
and being able to exploit them really
efficiently.
What I like about his tweet is the keep
it simple aspect, right? And I think a
lot of time, myself included, um when
I'm approaching a target, I way
overcomplicate my my like hacking
methodology. Like I'm trying way outside
the box techniques. I'm trying all these
crazy
edge case like, oh maybe this is
possible, maybe this is possible. Let me
try this crazy thing.
That is fine sometimes and a lot of
times that will and I I end up being a
bug, but it it's a lot more um sort of
like shot in the dark than it needs to
be. And I like that concept of keeping
it simple and identifying what you're
dealing with. Like, what are the assets?
Same thing, but more like web
application. Like, so what are the
parameters? Um what are the
technologies? Is it JSON? Is it XML? Uh
is it is it web based? The APIs thing
still applies, right? Are there APIs?
Great question. Um
can you brute force it? Is there a path?
Um how does it handle when you give it
an array instead of a string? Like
all these types of different things, um
understanding the different pieces. And
we've talked about this like as you go
deep on a target, you build out sort of
a mental mesh uh or map of what what the
target is, how it works, the different
pieces that connect to each other, and
what things talk to what, and how data
travels from one part of the application
to another part of the application. Um
and I think that is
potentially more useful than doing sort
of that Like the recon approach is
almost completely separate, but
different, right? Like it's the same,
but but but different where yes, you're
understanding the basics from like a
architecture level versus you're
understanding the basics from an
application level. Um and I think like
keeping it simple and just understanding
the fundamentals of what you're hacking
on is good regardless of how you're
doing it, whether that's figuring out
how the routing is working from a DNS
level or figuring out how the routing is
working from a path level.
You know, this is this is this is a deep
this is a deep one, dude. You know, cuz
there there's a couple there's a couple
things here. Like like you mentioned,
there's this whole concept of recon
within the the main app, too. You know,
understanding
where the APIs are in the main app,
where you know, how data flows, how the
JS looks. Like there's there's internal
recon as well. It um app internal recon
that I think is very important and
applying those same
principles of of what Naffy does here as
a as a recon hacker um
as a wide-scale recon hacker too,
um hacking in inside an application.
Those concepts are very applicable. What
Where the paths? Um you know, uh where
you know, what parameters are they
taking? Just like you said. I really
like that. That's really good.
The other thing that's kind of struck me
as I'm talking about this
is like
maybe maybe
maybe I'm playing it safe. Maybe the
reason why I like
hacking the main app is because there's
always functionality there.
There's always there's always impact
there.
And
that's for certain.
Whereas with recon, it kind of feels
like a big question mark to me.
You know, it's like it's like am I going
to find an asset? Okay, is that asset
going to have anything that I can I can
touch on it, you know, like without
auth?
It or can I figure out a way to auth
into it? You know, okay, is there any
functionality on this weird host in the
middle of nowhere? You know, can I guess
the parameters? Can I guess the path?
You know, it's just there's so many
question marks for me.
But
you do see people like Naffy and Shubs
pop these in in Corbin for that matter,
pop these these crazy crits because they
find some back-end admin host that has
no auth. And those kind of crits are not
crits, to be perfectly honest, that I
run across ever
because I'm not I'm not doing that.
Yeah. Um and so I don't know, man. I'm
going to put some more thought into that
from from uh a hacker perspective
because
it kind of reminds me like
it kind of reminds me of the whole um
I'm trying salaryman is not the word in
English. That's a Japanese word, but
it's like uh you know, the the the
traditionally employed, the W-2 employee
versus the entrepreneur, right? It's
like there's so many questions. There's
so much uncertainty. There's so much
struggle that goes into the entrepreneur
life.
Um and you know, versus this really
stable, really consistent, always going
to have your bills paid money that that
comes from a W-2.
Um but for me, the trade-off has been
great. You know, I I've loved it. I I
I've I've I've been able to push that
uncertainty and really enjoy being an
entrepreneur or a self-employed. So
maybe you you kind of
Do you see the parallel that I'm trying
to make there between like
Yeah. Yeah, I totally see the parallel.
I think like
for recon, the interesting thing about
recon is yeah, cat. The interesting
thing about recon is it's not like what
almost every recon bug I found
has been
basically entirely separated from the
main app in terms of like
not not always impact, but like what is
actually what I'm finding there. Like a
lot of the times when I'm doing recon,
it is some random system
that does some random weird
functionality that shouldn't exist or
shouldn't be exposed and I'm not really
understanding like the core API or the
core
web app that maybe is using that service
somewhere along the way or what Like I'm
just seeing, oh this is a weird service.
I can exploit it in this way. Here's a
vulnerability. Um and that's very
different from like, hey, on your main
web app, there's an XSS that leads to
account takeover, right? That's very
specific like application level, user
level type functionality vulnerabilities
versus almost configuration
vulnerabilities. So they're they're very
like
different buckets, but they apply to
each other very similar where
you know, it it it's the same thing of
like you want to understand what you're
looking at and you want to be able to
like identify like, oh this is a weird
target. Like, why does this domain
return a blank page instead of a 404 or
something like that? And digging into
that and identifying where to go from a
blank page for a lot of people can be a
lot more difficult than just
logging into the web app and clicking
all the buttons and finding, you know,
some endpoint within the JS or some
functionality within the client side
that is is vulnerable. Um so I think
it's a very different skill set and it's
like when you go to the gym and you do
legs versus arms, like it's just a
different muscle group. And you know,
you can be super jacked uh
on your on your on your arms and stuff
and then you got little little toothpick
legs.
Yeah, yeah, I built a home gym recently
and I'm still struggling.
It's good to see you see you going after
that. Yeah, man, I I I tend to agree.
You know, I think it's I think it's just
different muscles um muscle groups, but
it's definitely food for thought of like
I wonder if I'm being intimidated out of
the recon game because of the levels of
uncertainty. But at the end of the day,
there's uncertainty with the main app,
too, of like is there going to be
anything to find there? Um but at least
the functionality is there, right? And
that's what I kind of like. Um the
guarantee that the functionality will be
there and there's going to be something
for me to work with. Um whereas, you
know, in recon, there's no guarantees
about whether there will be something to
work with or not.
So.
Yep. And even with recon, um it's not
all the same. Like there's there's like
the recon that Naggly does and like
Mochan does and then there's the recon
that like Naffy does or J Hack's does
where like for J Hack's and Naffy, that
recon is to find new assets. For Naggly
and Mochan, that recon is to exploit
vulnerabilities.
Um like
ready vulnerabilities, right? Um and
they have like nuclei templates and
stuff like that that are like looking
for specific things to pop on these
hosts. Whereas, I think when Naffy finds
a host that looks interesting, he like
dives in on it and like
goes everywhere just trying to find some
sort of entry point or some sort of
thing. He's not looking for like
is this running Spring Boot and can I
can I, you know, execute this specific
CVE, right? It's it's it's a bit of a
different process um even within just
like the recon sphere.
But going deep as a whole, like go deep
for sure. Keep it simple, go deep and
and understand what you're looking at.
way to end it, man.